突变第三型
你的移动: 相进马四。
Your move: bishop to knight four.
我的移动: 马进车三。
My move: knight to rook three.
可怜的孩子, 你快要输了，不是吗？
Poor baby, you're startin' to lose it, aren't ya ?
你的移动: 王进车一。
Your move: king to rook one.
我的移动: 车进马六。
My move: rook to knight six.
将死！将死！
Checkmate. Checkmate.
你这作弊的婊子
You cheatin' bitch.
乔德斯，他在干嘛？
Childs, what's he doin' ?
围着营地盘旋。
Circlin' the camp.
他是谁？
Who is he ?
- 上面写着诺格什么的。 - 那是挪威人。
- Said Norge or something on the side. - That's Norwegian.
- 乔治，你没事吧？ - 还好，还好，我没事。
- George, are you okay ? - Yeah, yeah, I'm okay.
那边怎么回事？
Yeah. What's goin' on down there ?
看！
Watch it !
放松！
Easy.
放松！放松！
Easy. Easy.
放松！好！
Easy. Yes.
该死的冬天头一星期！
First goddamn week of winter.
哦，快点，只缝四针。 只不过是轻微的擦伤。
Oh, come on. Four stitches. Barely grazed ya.
他们飞这么低，到底要干什么！
What were they doing flying that low,
- 向狗还有我们射击？ - 嗯，发疯了吧！
- shooting at a dog, at us ? - Hmm, stir-crazy,
“幽居病”？谁知道呢
cabin fever, who knows ?
美国31号, 呼叫麦克马都。 请回话，完毕。
U.S. Number 31, calling McMurdo. Come in, over.
美国31号, 呼叫麦克马都。 紧急情况！请回话，完毕。
U.S. number 31, calling McMurdo, urgent ! Come in, over.
太好了！
Great.
- 快点，快点。 - 没有人！
- Come on, come on. - Nobody !
没有人？一定要与人联系上！任何人都行！ 必须报告这里的混乱局面！
Nobody ? Get ahold of somebody. Get ahold of anybody ! We gotta report this mess !
看，在两星期内我办不到。
Look, I haven't been able to reach shit in two weeks !
我怀疑在这整个大陆上是否 有人对其他人说话。
I doubt if anybody's talked to anybody on this entire continent,
而你就想让我向别人求援！
and you want me to reach somebody !
也许美国和挪威开战了。
Maybe we at war with Norway.
我想知道什么时候El Capitan能有 机会使用他的玩具枪。
I was wondering when EI Capitan was gonna get a chance to use his popgun.
- 他们在那儿驻扎了多长时间了？ - 据说只有8个星期。
- How long they been stationed there ? - It says here only eight weeks.
- 那还不足以使人变疯。 - 胡说, 布瓦纳。
- That's not long enough for guys to go bonkers. - Bullshit, Bwana.
五分钟就足够把一个人击倒了。
Five minutes is enough to put a man over down here.
- 真可恶！ - 我是说，你们看帕尔马。
- Damn straight. - I mean, look at Palmer.
自从第一天开始， 他就这么独来独往。
He been the way he is since the first day.
- 他们一共有多少人？ - 最初是有十个。
- How many in their party ? - They started with ten.
- 现在还剩八个。 - 你怎么知道？
- There'd be eight others left. - How do we know ?
在他们找到我们之前，他们就都疯 了，自相残杀。
Guys as crazy as that could have done a lot of damage to their own before they got to us.
- 我们什么也做不了。 - 哦，当然能。我去他们那。
- Nothing we can do. - Oh, yes there is. I want to go up.
- 在这样的天气吗？ - 我们开始吧？
- In this weather ? - Bennings ?
- 风稍后会停止一小会儿。 - 一小会儿？
- Winds are gonna let up a tad next couple of hours. - A tad ?
我不能容忍（开枪打我）这种事， （去挪威基地）只有一小段路。
Can't condone it much myself, but it is a short haul.
一小时去， 一小时回来。
An hour there, an hour back.
- 妈的，博士。我会载你的。 - 算了吧，帕尔马。
- Shit, Doc, I'll give you the lift. No problem. - Forget it, Palmer.
谢谢你能认真考虑。
Thanks for thinkin' about it though.
装着煤油， 15罐。
Loaded with kerosene. I count 15 cans.
- 麦克瑞德！ - 麦克，带上装备。
- MacReady ! - Mac, get your gear on.
- 大概有一个星期天气会不太好， 我们是离他们最近的。 - 我飞过去也没什么，博士。
- It may not clear up for a week, and we're the closest to 'em. - It's all right by me, Doc.
- 我只想让你知道， 我们这是在冒险！ - 别唱反调，麦克瑞德！
- I'm just letting you know we're taking a chance. - Quit griping, MacReady.
如果我们遇上大暴风雪， 你就来挖你的博士和飞行员吧。
If we get caught in a white-out, you can scratch one doctor and one pilot.
这天就是这样， 你一起飞，天气就会变好了。
This is real thin. It'll clear as soon as you get up.
你决定吧，麦克！
It's up to you, Mac.
如果你不想飞， 我们就不飞过去。
If you don't wanna fly, we don't fly.
- 你真的想救这些发了疯的瑞典人？ - 是挪威人。
- You really wanna save those crazy Swedes, huh ? - Norwegians.
- 哪条路，博士？ - 西南方向。
- Which way, Doc ? - Southwest.
我腾不出手，只好由你来看地图了。
You have to read the map 'cause I'm gonna be busy.
麦克真的去了？
Mac's really taking it up, huh ?
他知道他在作什么。
He knows what he's doing.
诺斯，你能不能把那该死的东西关上？ 我正准备睡会儿觉。 我今天中了枪。
Nauls, will you turn that crap down ? I'm trying to get some sleep. I was shot today.
- 好吧，布瓦纳。 （Stevie Wonder的名曲Superstition）
- Oui, Bwana. Will do. - Very superstitious
Writing's on the wall
Very superstitious
有人吗？
Anybody there ?
嗨, 瑞典人？
Hey, Sweden ?
他们不是瑞典人，麦克。 他们是挪威人。
They're not Swedish, Mac, they're Norwegian.
麦克！
Mac !
上帝，这里到底发生了什么？
My God ! What the hell happened here ?
快点，博士！
Come on, Doc.
便携式视频设备。
Portable video unit.
- 什么事？ - 都是用挪威文写的。
- Anything ? - It's all in Norwegian.
- 你在干什么，博士？ - 这可能是很重要的东西。 我想把它带回去。
- What are ya doin', Doc ? - It could be important work. I wanna take it back with us.
要来不及了，我们快点儿！
It's gettin' late. Let's hurry it up.
我再查查最后几个房间。
I'll check out the last few rooms.
嗨，考柏，到这儿来！
Hey, Copper, come here !
也许他们找到了化石， 冻在冰层中的动物残骸。
Maybe they found a fossil, the remains of some animal buried in the ice,
- 他们把冰破开，取了出来。 - 可那东西在哪？看这个！
- and they chopped it out. - But where is it ? Look at this.
这是什么？
What is that ?
这是人还是什么？
Is that a man in there or something ?
不管它是什么， 他们匆忙中烧焦了它。
Whatever it is, they burned it up in a hurry.
帮我找个铲子，博士。
Help me find a shovel, Doc.
- 我们找到了这个。 - 上帝啊！
- We found this. - Jesus Christ !
布莱尔，我希望你马上 作一下尸体解剖。
Blair, I'd like you to start an autopsy right away.
- 联络到什么人了吗？ - 联络谁？
- Did you reach anybody yet ? - Reach anybody ?
数千公里方圆内都 没有什么人啊，老兄！
We're a thousand miles from nowhere, man,
在情况转好之前，也许会变得更糟。
and it's gonna get a hell of a lot worse before it gets any better !
好，坚持住。 温都思，坚持住。
Well, stick to it, Windows, stick to it.
从生理学角度来看，这个挪威人 没有什么问题。
Nothin' wrong with this Norwegian, physiologically anyway.
- 没有吸毒，没有喝酒，什么都没有。 - 嗯。
- No drugs, no alcohol, nothin'. - Hmm.
好吧，不管怎么说， 就像我们所见的这样。
Well, what we got here is what appears to be, anyway,
全套内脏器官正常。
a normal set of internal organs.
心脏，
Heart,
肺，肾，肝，
Lungs, kidneys, liver,
肠子。
intestines.
看起来都很正常。
Seem to be normal.
（综艺节目录像）
...one, door number two and door number three.
I think that Dawn Screen here has got the most to trade in. I went to you first.
You brought your friend, Anna. You've been consulting Anna all through the show.
- 这节目的结果我都知道了。
- You may as well consult her one more time. - I know how this one ends.
克拉克，你能把这杂毛狗 牵到它该去的地方吗？
Clark, will you put this mutt with the others where it belongs ?
好的，没问题。
Yeah, okay.
走吧。
Go ahead.
走吧。 你还在等什么？
Go ahead. What are you waiting for ?
我不知道 那里究竟发生了什么。
I don't know what the hell's in there.
- 不管是什么，太怪了！ - 本宁斯，去找乔德斯。
- It's weird and pissed off, whatever it is. - Bennings, go get Childs.
这是什么？怎么了？
What is this ? What's goin' on ?
- 嗨，帕尔马，这是什么？ - 我不知道。
- Hey, Palmer, what is this ? - I don't know.
乔德斯！ 麦克想要喷火器。
Childs ! Mac wants the flamethrower !
- 麦克想要什么？ - 不是说了吗！
- Mac wants the what ? - That's what he said !
- 现在去！ - 妈的！
- Now, move ! - Damn it !
- 退后！ - 麦克，那是什么？
- Stand back. - Mac, what is it ?
- 不！不！上帝！
- No ! No ! God !
- 不要！不要！不！ - 回来！回来！
- Don't ! Don't ! No ! - Get back ! Get back !
- 到这儿来，烧它。
- Get your ass over here ! Burn it !
妈的！乔德斯，烧了它！
Damn it, Childs, torch it !
哦，我的上帝！
Oh, my God.
哦！哦！
Oh ! Ohh !
看。婊子养的。
Look. Son of a bitch.
我们所谈论的其实是一种生物...
What we're talking about here is an organism...
它模仿其它生物的形态。 而且可以非常完美的模仿。
that imitates other life-forms, and it imitates them perfectly.
当这玩意儿袭击我们的狗，
When this thing attacked our dogs,
它试图去消化它们，吸收它们。
it tried to digest 'em, absorb them.
而且在它形态转变过程中， 它自己的细胞也在模仿狗的细胞。
And in the process shape its own cells to imitate them.
这是举个例子。 那不是狗。
This, for instance. That's not dog.
是那东西模拟的。
It's imitation.
在它有时间完成前， 我们要先找到它。
We got to it before it had time to finish.
完成什么？
Finish what ?
完成模仿其它的狗。
Finish imitating these dogs.
放松，放松，很好。
Easy. Easy. Good.
- 放松，放松。
- Easy. Easy.
- 克拉克？ - 什么事？
- Clark ? - Yeah ?
你有没有注意到这些狗有异常？ 不管是哪方面的！
Did you notice anything strange about the dog, anything at all ?
异常？没有。
Strange ? No.
这狗跑到娱乐室干什么？
What was the dog doing in the rec room ?
我不知道。
I don't know.
这些日子它一直在营地里转悠。
He was just wandering around camp all day.
你是说直到昨天晚上这狗才被关进狗舍？
Are you sayin' to me the dog wasn't put in the kennel until last night ?
-就是这样。 -你单独和这狗待了多长时间？
-Right. -How long were you alone with that dog ?
我不知道，一个小时？ 也许是一个半小时。
I don't know, an hour, hour and a half maybe.
干什么这样看着我？
What the hell you lookin' at me like that for ?
- 不知道。 - 什么？
- I don't know. - What ?
我不知道。 也许没什么。
I don't know. It's probably nothin'.
也许根本就没什么。
It's nothin' at all.
还有多少这种无聊的录象？
How much more of this crap is there ?
- 哦，大概九小时。 - 录象里看不出什么东西。
- Oh, nine hours I'd say. - We can't learn anything from this.
我不这么觉得。
Guess not.
他们在哪拍的这些？
Where'd they take these shots ?
看起来象是花费了 他们很多时间...
Seems like they were spending a lot of their time...
在他们营地东北五、六英里的一个地点。
in a little place northeast of their camp about five or six miles.
那是什么？
What's that ?
看起来象是什么东西埋在冰层下。
It looks like something buried under the ice.
看那个 他们正在埋设铝热剂炸药。
And look at that, they're planting thermite charges.
不管它是什么, 比你发现的那块冰要大。
Whatever it was, it was bigger than the block of ice you found.
这儿。
Here.
就是它， 这儿就是他们花费了大量时间的地方。
This is it, the place where they were spending most of their time.
- 外面情况很差. 风速35节. - 去他妈的. 不管怎样我要去
- Pretty nasty out. 35 knots. - Screw it. I'm gonna go up anyway.
正东半英里。
Half a mile due east.
我的天！你估计这已经在冰中埋多久了 ?
Jesus ! How long you figure this has been in the ice ?
冰层运动令这东西
Well, the backscatter effect's been bringin' things up...
从很深的地方移上来，要花很长时间
from way down around here for a long time.
我得说...这个... 埋藏它的这些冰层...
I'd say- I'd say the ice it's buried in...
最少有10万年的历史了。
is 100,000 years old at least.
- 挪威人把冰层炸开了。 - 对。
- And those Norwegians blew it up. - Yeah.
我不知道。
I don't know.
几千年以前， 它坠落了，这些变异体…
Thousands of years ago it crashes and this thing...
被弹射出来，或者爬出来， 然后死了,冻结在冰层里。
gets thrown out or crawls out and it ends up freezing in the ice.
- 我才不相信这种鬼话邪说。 - 乔德斯，
- I just cannot believe any of this voodoo bullshit. - Childs,
这种事情就是会发生，老兄。
happens all the time, man.
他们就象苍蝇一样从天空中冲下来。
They're fallin' out of the skies like flies.
政府知道真相， 对吧，麦克？
Government knows all about it. Right, Mac ?
- 你相信这些鬼话吗？布莱尔？ - 乔德斯？
- Do you believe any of this voodoo bullshit, Blair ? - Childs ?
乔德斯，听说过“上帝的战车”吗，老兄。
Childs, Chariots Of The Gods, man.
他们实际控制了南美。
They practically own South America.
我是说，他们教给印加人 他们所知的一切。
I mean, they taught the Incas everything they know.
所以，就这样，麦克瑞德。
So, come on now, MacReady.
挪威人发现了这个...
The Norwegians get ahold of this...
- 然后他们把它从冰里挖出来。 - 是的，格瑞，挖了出来。
- and they dig it up out of the ice. - Yes, Garry, they dig it up,
他们把它运了回来。 它被解冻了。
they cart it back, it gets thawed out,
它醒了，也许不是在最好的情况下。
wakes up, probably not in the best of moods.
- 我不知道。 - 你们这些没教养的家伙哪一个...
- I don't know- - Which one of you disrespectful men...
把他的脏内衣扔到 厨房的垃圾桶里了，嗯？
been tossin' his dirty drawers in the kitchen trash can, huh ?
从现在开始，我要我的厨房保持清洁！ 行吗？没有细菌！
From now on, I want my kitchen clean, all right ? Germ free !
现在，这个他妈的在冰层里 待了几千年的东西怎么醒过来的？
Now, how's this motherfucker wake up after thousands of years in the ice ?
- 并且它怎么会象一条狗？ - 我不知道。
- And how can it look like a dog ? - I don't know how.
因为它和我们完全不同。看。
'Cause it's different than us, see.
因为它来自外太空。 你想我能怎么样？问他！
'Cause it's from outer space. What do you want from me ? Ask him.
你相信这些吗？布莱尔？
You buy any of this, Blair ?
麦克，我们正在把那些东西。
Mac, we're movin' those things...
从实验室搬到储藏室。
out of the lab into the storeroom.
你能过来拿走个人的杂物吗？
Can you come get your stuff ?
好的，马上来，博士。
Be there in a minute, Doc.
从那门过去。
Through the door.
对，就是那儿。 就是那儿。
Right over there. Right over there.
对不起，麦克。 你还得拿走自己的东西。
Sorry, Mac. You have to move your stuff-
博士说我们必须要把它们关在这儿 并且锁起来。
Doc says we gotta stash 'em in here and lock 'em up.
- 我一定要和你谈谈。 - 我不想谈什么了，福齐斯。
- I have to talk to you. - I'm tired of talking, Fuchs.
我只想回小屋歇歇，喝点酒。
I just want to get up to my shack and get drunk.
- 麦克，这很重要。 - 什么？
- Mac, it's important. - What is it ?
- 去外面说吧。 - 外面有零下40度。
- Outside. - It's 40 below outside.
那就到车里说. 帮帮忙，麦克。
In the Thiokol. Please, Mac.
我们应该烧掉这些东西。
We ought to just burn these things.
怎能烧掉世纪大发现！
Can't burn the find of the century.
那可是能让人得诺贝尔奖的东西！
That's gonna win somebody the Nobel Prize.
你有钥匙吗？
You got the keys ?
找格瑞去拿。 我要从这搬出点东西。
Get 'em from Garry. I want to get some stuff out of here.
布莱尔有点儿不对劲儿。
There's something wrong with Blair.
他把自己锁在房间不出来， 敲门他也不理。
He's locked in his room and won't answer the door.
- 我从实验室里拿了他的 一个笔记本，听这个 - 什么？
- I took one of his notebooks from the lab. Listen. - Yeah ?
“它可以在无数个行星上模仿无数 种生命形式。”
"It could have imitated a million life-forms on a million planets.
“它可以在任意时间变成他们中的 任意一个。”
It could change into any one of them at any time.
- “现在它想要变成地球上的生命形式了。” - 我觉得冷了。
- Now it wants life-forms on Earth-" - It's gettin' cold,
- 而且我已经两天没睡了。 - 等一下，麦克。
- and I haven't slept in two days. - Wait a minute, Mac.
“它需要独处，并接近它要吸收的 生命形式。”
"It needs to be alone and in close proximity with the life-form to be absorbed.
- 就像在黑暗中袭击猎物的变色龙。 - 布莱尔脑子没问题吧？
- The chameleon strikes in the dark." - Is Blair cracking up ?
妈的，麦克瑞德。 “在这些烧过的残骸里仍然有细胞的活动。”
Damn it, MacReady. "There's still cellular activity in these burned remains.
“它们还没有死。”
They're not dead yet."
我们走，本宁斯。 我必须要睡会儿了。
Let's go, Bennings. I gotta get some sleep.
妈的。
Holy shit.
去找博士。
Go get the doc.
- 我去找格瑞。 待会儿我们在布莱尔的房间见面。 - 好的。
- I'll get Garry. We'll meet in Blair's room. - All right.
本宁斯！
It's Bennings !
本宁斯就在那儿！ 麦克！我发誓它已经把他控制了！
Bennings was right there, Mac ! I swear it had ahold of him !
- 温都思，回来！离开他！ - 别碰他！
- Windows, get back ! Keep away from him ! - Don't touch him !
回来！退后！
Get back ! Stay back !
它不是本宁斯！
It isn't Bennings !
- 我的上帝！他身上发生了什么事？ - 如果它有时间完成变形，
- My God ! What was happening to him ? - If it had time to finish,
它就会在相貌，声音，甚至行为 上都完全和本宁斯一样！
it would have looked and sounded and acted just like Bennings !
- 我不知道你在说什么。 - 那是那些变异体中的一个。
- I don't know what you're saying. - That was one of those things,
正试图去模仿他，格瑞。
trying to imitate him, Garry.
- 快点。 麦克瑞德，我认识本宁斯已经有10年了！
- Come on. - MacReady, I've known Bennings for ten years.
他是我的朋友。
He's my friend.
我们必须把剩下的变异体烧掉。
We gotta burn the rest of them.
好吧，都退后。
All right, step back.
你确定所有的都在这儿了？
You sure that's all of 'em ?
我们彻底搜过仓库和实验室。
We cleaned out the storehouse, the lab.
没有其他的了。
There is nothing left.
布莱尔在哪儿？
Where's Blair ?
我找不到布莱尔了！
I can't find Blair.
其它人在哪儿？
Where's everybody else ?
温都思仍然在通信室 试图取得联系。
Windows is in the radio room still trying to get through.
其它的人在娱乐室。
Everyone else is in the rec room.
你继续， 我马上进来。
You go on. I'll be in in a minute.
布莱尔？
Blair ?
别进来！ 我有枪，还有斧子！
Don't come in here ! I got a gun ! I got an ax !
不行，你这个婊子养的！ 不要进来！你听明白了吗？
Don't, you son of a bitch ! Don't come in here ! You understand me ?
- 他有枪，麦克！ - 谁拦着我，我就杀了谁！
- He's got a gun, Mac ! - Anybody interferes, I'll kill 'im !
- 耶稣啊！
- Jesus !
- 他破坏了直升机的部件
- He smashed up some of the chopper pretty good.
乔德斯，去看看 他有没有弄坏牵引车。
Childs, go see if he got to the tractor.
没有人能过去，没有人！
Nobody gets in and out of here ! Nobody !
你们这群家伙以为我疯了！ 好，这太好了！
You guys think I'm crazy ! Well, that's fine !
你们大部分都不知道 这里究竟发生了什么！
Most of ya don't know what's going on around here !
而我知道你们中一些“东西”要干什么！
But I'm damn well sure some of you do !
基督啊！
Christ !
他弄坏了直升机和牵引车， 而且他还把剩下的狗给杀了。
He got most of the chopper and the tractor, and he's killed the rest of the dogs.
格瑞，等一下！等一下！
Garry, wait a minute ! Wait a minute !
好的，乔德斯， 绕到地图室那边去,
All right, Childs, go around to the map room door,
- 吸引他说话。 - 好的。
- talk to him. - Okay.
继续。
Go on.
诺瑞斯，从实验室搬张桌子！
Norris, get a table from the lab.
你认为那个变异体只是想变成一种动物？
- Do you think that thing wanted to be an animal ?
没有什么狗能在这么冷的天气 跑完上千英里的路程。
No dogs make it a thousand miles through the cold.
不，你不会知道的。
No, you don't understand !
那个变异体是想变成我们！
That thing wanted to be us !
只要一个细胞，它就可以 模仿地球上的任何东西。
A cell gets out, it could imitate everything on the face of the earth !
- 什么都不能阻止它。 - 好，布莱尔，
- And nothing could stop it ! - Okay, Blair,
现在来吧，你不会伤害任何人的。
come on now, you don't want to hurt anybody.
- 我要杀了你！
- I'll kill you !
干得好，麦克瑞德。 我很抱歉。
Good shot, MacReady. Excuse me.
- 很好，把他弄上来。 - 是。
- All right, bring him up. Lift him up. - Yeah.
- 好的，好的。
- Okay. Okay.
来吧，布莱尔。
Come on, Blair.
- 你的小屋怎么样？麦克瑞德？ - 我不想他待在我的小屋！
- What about your shack, MacReady ? - I don't want him in my shack.
我们会把他锁在工具间。
We'll lock him in the toolshed.
为什么我会在这儿？
Why am I in here ?
为了保护你自己，布莱尔， 还有我们。
For your own protection, Blair... and ours.
你怎么样了？老兄？
How you doin', old boy ?
我不知道还有谁可以相信。
I don't know who to trust.
我知道你的意思，布莱尔。
I know what you mean, Blair.
这些天来， 相互信任成了一件很困难的事。
Trust is a tough thing to come by these days.
告诉你什么
Tell you what,
为什么你不相信上帝？
why don't you just trust in the Lord ?
留意克拉克！
Watch Clark.
什么？
What ?
我说：“留意克拉克！”
I said, "Watch Clark."
密切留意他， 听明白了吗？
And watch him close, do you hear me ?
现在电台没了。
Now the radio's gone.
- 直升机也没了。 - 我们完全与世隔绝！
- So are the choppers. - We're completely cut off.
现在我们所能做的就只有藏起来， 直到春天救援队过来。
All we can do now is hole up 'til spring and wait for the rescue team.
不行，不能坐以待毙，这个营地的 某些人并不象表面那样是人类。
No, we don't wait. Somebody in this camp ain't what he appears.
现在也许只是我们中的一两个， 到了春天我们可能全都是变异体了。
Right now that may be one or two of us. By spring it could be all of us.
那么我们怎么知道谁是人类？
So how do we know who's human ?
如果我是一个变异体冒充的人， 一个完全一样的复制品，
If I was an imitation- a perfect imitation-
你怎么知道他是不是真的我？
how would you know if it was really me ?
有没有什么测试 可以识别？博士？
Is there some kind of test, Doc ?
哦，对啦，这也许可以。
Well, yeah... possibly.
- 我已经考虑过了一个血清测试。 - 那是怎么一回事？
- I've been thinking about a blood serum test. - What's that ?
我们可以从每个人 身上抽取血液样品。
We could take a sample of each person's blood.
把它和没有污染的血液混合。
We could mix it with uncontaminated blood.
如果产生反应， 就能知道谁不是人类。
I suppose if there's a reaction, we'd know who isn't human.
我们有全部血液样品在贮藏室里。
We've got whole blood in storage.
这儿，开始干吧！
Here, start working on it.
看着克拉克。
Keep an eye on Clark.
他和那只狗接触很多。
He was close to that dog.
是，是。
Yeah. Yeah.
麦克，我们需要布莱尔的帮助！ 他是唯一一个...
Mac, we need Blair's help. He's the only one...
- 知道这个变异体能干什么的人。 - 这件事上他做的太过了，福齐斯。
- who knows what this organism is capable of. - He's too far gone, Fuchs.
找到他余下的笔记本， 开始进行测试。
But get the rest of his notebooks and start going through them.
格瑞！嗨！大家都快过来！
Garry ! Hey, you guys, come here !
什么？
What ?
- 有人动过这些血液了！ - 什么？
- Somebody got to the blood ! - What ?
- 克拉克在哪儿？ - 在这儿。
- Where's Clark ? - Right here.
等一会儿，等一会儿， 柜子门被别开了吗？
Wait a minute, wait a minute. Was this broken into ?
没有，锁没有被弄坏。
No, the lock is undamaged.
- 有人打开过门，又把它关上锁好了。 - 很好。
- Somebody opened it, closed it, then locked it. - Great.
谁有权使用它？
Who's got access to it ?
我想只有我一个人。
I guess I'm the only one.
我只有一把钥匙。
And I got the only key.
那么测试还能继续进行吗？博士？
Would that test have worked, Doc ?
- 哦，我想还可以。 - 其它人这么想。
- Oh, I think so, yes. - Somebody else sure as hell thought so.
好吧，谁还用过那把钥匙？
Well, who else could have used that key ?
没有！只有考柏 可以随时拿到钥匙。
Nobody ! I just give it to Copper whenever he needs it !
- 有谁从你这儿拿过钥匙吗，博士？ - 我看不出有人能拿到。
- Could anybody have gotten it from you, Doc ? - I don't see how.
我一用完就会马上归还的。
As soon as I'm finished, I return it right away.
很好。
Great.
- 你上次用它是在什么时候？ - 一天以前或更早。
- When was the last time you used it ? - A day or so ago.
我猜想有人把它从我这儿拿走了。
I suppose somebody could have lifted it off me-
哦，看看吧，钥匙环一直在 你带子上钩着。
Oh, come on ! That key ring is always hooked to your belt.
- 每个人都有嫌疑。
- Accusing everybody-
停手！不值得这样！
Stop it now ! It ain't worth it !
- 考柏是唯一一个和它有点联系的人。 - 等一下！
- Copper's the only one who's got any business with it. - Wait a minute !
- 你有过几次机会来这里。 - 博士，考虑考虑测试吧。
- You've been in here on several occasions ! - Doc thought of the test.
- 那就可以排除他了吗？胡说！ - 为什么他要拿?
- That clears him ? Bullshit ! - Why would he take-
- 你们都给我闭嘴！ - 温都思！ - 温都思！
- Shut up, man ! - Windows ! - Windows !
把那个放下！
Put that down.
- 不！ - 我会打穿你的脑袋！
- No. - I'll put this right through your head.
你们这些家伙听格瑞的， 让他下命令吗？
You guys gonna listen to Garry, let him give the orders ?
他可能是那些变异体中的一个！
He could be one of those things !
温都思，等一会儿。 放松，别紧张！
Windows, wait a minute. Just take it easy.
把枪放下！放下它！
Put the gun down. Put it down.
- 格瑞，你不想伤害任何人。 - 退后。
- Garry, you don't want to hurt anybody. - Get back.
把枪放在地板上。
On the floor.
已经放下了。
It's on the floor.
我不了解考柏。
I don't know about Copper,
但是我告诉你， 我没有靠近过那些血液。
but I give you my word, I did not go near that blood.
但是我想如果其它人要主导测试
But I guess you'll all feel a little easier...
你们都会放松点儿
if somebody else was in charge.
诺瑞斯，我看没有人反对你了。
Norris, I can't see anybody objecting to you.
我很抱歉，伙计们， 但是我…我不干。
I'm sorry, fellas, but I-I-I'm not up to it.
- 我来吧。 - 你去死还差不多。
- I'll take it. - Like hell you will.
应该让更冷静的人来， 乔德斯。
It should be somebody a little more even tempered, Childs.
很好。
All right.
我知道我是人类。
I know I'm human.
如果你们都是变异体， 那么你们现在就会袭击我。
And if you were all these things, then you'd just attack me right now.
所以你们中的一些仍然是人类。
So some of you are still human.
这个变异体并不想暴露自己。
This thing doesn't want to show itself.
它想把自己隐藏在模仿体中。
It wants to hide inside an imitation.
不到万不得已，它是不会向我们开战的。
It'll fight if it has to,
它暴露在露天就很脆弱。
but it's vulnerable out in the open.
如果它把我们取代了，
If it takes us over,
那么它就没什么敌人了。
then it has no more enemies,
没有人来杀死它。
nobody left to kill it.
那么它就赢了。
And then it's won.
6个小时内会有暴风雪刮过来。
There's a storm hitting us in six hours.
我们必须分出谁是谁。
We're gonna find out who's who.
很好，博士。格瑞和克拉克挪开， 和其它人保持距离。
All right, Doc, Garry and Clark move over there away from the others.
诺瑞斯，你和乔德斯给他们 注射吗啡，捆住看好他们。
Norris, you and Childs shoot 'em up with morphine. Tie 'em down and watch 'em.
-福齐斯，你开始作新测试。 -我需要博士的帮助。
-Fuchs, you start workin' on a new test. -I need Doc's help.
是的，你们不能给我麻醉。
Yeah, you don't want to drug me.
麦克，我可不是囚犯！
Mac, I'm not a prisoner !
我自己来， 你会把针头弄断在我胳膊里的。
Here, let me do it. You're gonna break the needle in my arm.
不，博士。 他做的很好。
No, Doc. He's doin' a real fine job.
我干完后一定要把这个磁带藏起来。
I'm gonna hide this tape when I'm finished.
如果我们中没有人能幸免， 至少也有一些记录吧。
If none of us make it, at least there'll be some kind of record.
暴风雪已经猛烈的 在营地刮了48小时。
Storm's been hitting us hard now for 48 hours.
事情依然没有什么进展。
We still have nothing to go on.
我想到一件事。
One other thing.
我认为当它取代你的身体 的时候会撕开你的衣服。
I think it rips through your clothes when it takes you over.
温都思发现了一些撕破的内衣裤， 但是名字标签不见了。
Windows found some shredded long johns, but the name tag was missing.
任何人都有可能。
They could be anybody's.
没有人--
Nobody-
没有人能相互信任。
Nobody trusts anybody now.
大家都很累。
And we're all very tired.
互相之间都不信任。
Nobody trusts anybody now.
现在我所能做的只有一件事，
There's nothing else I can do.
那就是等待。
Just wait.
- R.J. 麦克瑞德，直升机飞行员， 美国基地31号。
- R.J. MacReady, helicopter pilot, U.S. Outpost Number 31.
你来有什么事吗？
You come up with anything yet ?
有点儿想法。
One or two ideas.
但是，麦克瑞德， 我们一直在想
But, MacReady, I've been thinking.
如果这个变异体身上的一小 部分就足以替代整个生物体，
If a small particle of this thing is enough to take over an entire organism,
那么每个人都应该自备食物。
then everyone should prepare their own meals.
我建议我们只吃罐头。
I suggest we only eat out of cans.
很好。
All right.
谁？
Who's that ?
有人看到福齐斯吗？
Anybody see Fuchs ?
有人把实验室的保险丝给弄坏了。
Somebody blew out a fuse in the lab.
灯熄灭一个小时了， 我们必须找到他。
Lights were out for an hour. Any one of us could have gotten to him.
好的， 必须找到他。
All right, we gotta find him.
诺斯，你来和我 一起看看外面。
Nauls, why don't you come with me and we'll look outside.
帕尔马，你和温都思去查看里面。
Palmer, you and Windows check the inside.
我不和温都思一起去！
I ain't goin' with Windows.
我和乔德斯一起
I ain't goin' with him. I'll go with Childs.
- 喂，你他妈的，帕尔马！ - 我不想和你去！
- Hey, fuck you, Palmer ! - I ain't goin' with you !
- 谁说我想让你和我去的？ - 好了，都别他妈吵了！
- Who says I want you goin' with me ? - All right, cut the bullshit !
温都思，你和我们去，诺瑞斯， 你待在这儿。
Windows, you come with us. Norris, you stay here.
如果有谁不老实，你就把他给烧烤了。 你听到任何声响，你就打开警报器。
Any of them move, you fry 'em. You hear anything at all, you cut loose on the sirens.
不管发生什么 我们20分钟后回来会合
We all meet back here in 20 minutes, regardless !
不管是谁，每个人都把同伴看好。
And everybody watch whoever you're with,
不要散开
real close.
嗨，布莱尔！
Hey, Blair !
布莱尔，你看到福齐斯了吗？
Blair, have you seen Fuchs ?
我可不想还这样在外面待着。
I don't want to stay out here anymore.
我想回里面去。
I want to come back inside.
有点不对劲， 我听到外面有点儿不对劲。
Funny things. I hear funny things out here.
- 你遇到福齐斯了吗？ - 它不是福齐斯。
- Have you come across Fuchs ? - It ain't Fuchs.
它不是福齐斯。
It ain't Fuchs.
我不准备伤害任何人， 我也没什么异常。
I'm not gonna harm anybody, and there's nothing wrong with me.
就算以前有，现在也全都好了。
And if there was, I'm all better now.
我想回到里面去。 你答应过我的。
I'd like to come back inside. You got my promise.
再说吧。
We'll see.
嗨，等一下。 等一下，老兄。
Hey, wait a minute. Wait a minute, man.
我想回到里面去， 你没弄懂我的话吗？
I want to come back inside. Don't you understand ?
我很好，我感觉很好。 我不会伤害任何人。
I'm all right. I'm much better. I won't harm anybody.
你必须让我进去。
You gotta let me come back inside.
等下！
Hold it !
是福齐斯吗？
Is it Fuchs ?
是的。
Yeah.
变异体把他烧死了？
Why would it burn him ?
是照明烟火， 也许是他本来是想烧它的。
Flare. Maybe he tried to burn it.
也许在那东西控制他以前，
Maybe he burned himself...
他就自焚了。
before it could get to him.
太“好”了！现在我们怎么办？
Great ! Now what are we gonna do ?
你进去。 告诉其它人我们找到福齐斯了。
You go inside. Tell the others we found Fuchs.
我们就在里面待着，直到我们能 做点什么。
We'll be in as soon as we can.
- 我们准备去哪儿？ - 去我的小屋。
- Where are we goin' ? - Up to my shack.
- 到底干嘛？ - 因为我离开的时候，灯是关上的。
- What the hell for ? - 'Cause when I left, I turned the lights off.
他们出去多长时间了？
How long have they been out there ?
40...45分钟。
Forty, forty-five minutes.
我们最好把外面的门都封上。
We better start closing off the outside doors.
嗨！你们都过来！
Hey ! All of you come here !
打开！ 打开这扇门！打开！打开！
Open up ! Open up this door ! Open up ! Open up !
关上门。
Close that door.
- 麦克瑞德在哪儿？
- Where's MacReady ?
- 在他的小屋旁，我把他给摆脱了。 - 把他给摆脱了？
- I cut him loose of the line up by his shack. - Cut him loose ?
是的。我们在他住的地方检查了一下。
Yeah. We were up checkin' around his place.
我发现了这个。
I found this.
看。
Look.
塞在他自己的燃油取暖炉里。
It was stashed in his own oil furnace.
风也许把它吹跑了， 但是我想他没看见我找到它。
Wind must have dislodged it, but I don't think he saw me find it.
在回来的路上， 我肯定抢在他前面了。
I made sure I got ahead of him on the towline on the way back.
我把他摆脱了。
I cut him loose.
- 麦克瑞德？ - 他是那些东西中的一个。
- MacReady ? - He's one of them.
- 它什么时候取代他的？ - 我不知道。
- When did it get to him ? - I don't know.
什么时候，什么地点都可以。
It could have been anytime, anywhere.
- 如果它取代了他。 - 看，乔德斯，快点！
- lf it did get to him. - Look, Childs, come on !
- 当灯熄灭的时候！ - 那正是好时候。
- When the lights went out ! - That would have been the perfect time.
对！你说有人不见了。 那么，温都思，当时你在哪儿？
Right ! You said guys were missing. And, Windows, where were you ?
帕尔马，我告诉过你， 他妈的给我闭嘴！
Palmer, I told you to shut the fuck up !
熄灯的时候，你们都在哪儿？
Where were you when the lights when out ?
那就是它所希望的： 让我们掉进互相对立的境地！
That's what it wants: to pit us against each other !
弟兄们！它是麦克瑞德！
Guys ! It's MacReady.
嘘！安静！
Shh !
- 我们把它打开。 - 该死，不！
- Let's open it. - Hell no !
- 你认为他已经被那些变异体 给侵入了？ - 他有充足的时间。
- Do you think he's changed into one of those things ? - He's had plenty of time.
- 如果是人的话， 是不会这么快就到这儿的 - 把门打开！
- Nothing human could have made it back here without a guideline. - Let's open it now !
- 为什么你这么着急想让他进来？ - 因为非常近！
- Why are you so damn anxious to let him in here ? - 'Cause it's so close !
- 也许是我们把它烧掉的最好机会。 - 不！
- May be our best chance to blow it away ! - No !
- 让它在外面冻死算了。 - 如果我们判断错误怎么办？
- Just let him freeze to death outside. - What if we're wrong about him?
- 怎么办？就是判断错误而已！
- Why, then we're wrong !
气窗碎了！
Supply window !
很好，很好！ 我们现在没有机会了！
All right, all right. We got no choice now !
妈的！ 他有钥匙！
Damn it ! He's got the keys !
怎么办？缆绳已经断了！
What's goin' on ? The towline snapped.
该死，乔德斯。 他知道是我砍了它。
That's bullshit, Childs. He knows damn well I cut it.
你死定了，麦克瑞德！
You're a dead man, MacReady !
或者说不管你是什么其他该死的东西！
Or a dead whatever the hell you are !
有人把我和整个营地 的一些家伙弄混了。
Anyone messes with me and the whole camp goes.
来啊，乔德斯，烧我啊。
Come on, Childs, burn me.
把喷火器放在地上然后退后。
Put those torches on the floor and back off.
退后。退到门口。
Back off. Way off.
- 你这个混蛋。 - 你也好不到哪去。
- You asshole. - You'd have done the same thing.
别和他争吵。
Don't argue with him.
其他的人在哪儿？
Where's the rest ?
帮帮忙，就是这样！
So help me, I mean it !
冷静，麦克瑞德。 冷静，老兄！快点！
It's cool, MacReady. It's cool, man ! Come on !
是的，是的，老兄。 放松。
Yeah, yeah, man. Just relax.
有人碰我的话，我们就同归于尽。
Anybody touches me, and we go.
他停止呼吸了！
He's not breathin' !
走吧，直到博士来。
Go untie the doc.
把他放到这里。 叫其他人来。
Get him in here. And bring the others.
从现在开始， 所有人都要在我的视线以内。
From now on, nobody gets out of my sight.
把他放在这儿。
Lay him there.
你们这些小朋友
So you sweethearts...
想来一个 小小的私刑集会吗，哼？
were about to have yourselves a little lynching party, huh ?
我可能不得不按常规结果你，乔德斯。
I might just have to put an end to you on general principles, Childs.
你们这些人中 谁把我的衣服塞进暖炉的?
Did it occur to the jury that anybody could have stuck some of my clothes up the furnace ?
我们可没那么做
We ain't buyin' that.
别在这儿斗嘴！
Quit that bickering over there !
温都思，把除颤器拿过来！
Windows, wheel that defibrillator over here !
在电极板上抹上导电膏！
Put some gel on those paddles !
你该去睡会儿了，麦克瑞德。
You're gonna have to sleep sometime, MacReady.
我的睡眠总是很浅，乔德斯。
I'm a real light sleeper, Childs.
如果有人试图叫醒我--
If anyone tries to wake me-
啊哈！
Uh-uh.
离床！
Clear !
- 离床！ - 离床。
- Clear ! - Clear.
- 我们太激动了，麦克瑞德！ - 回来！再等一下！
- We're on fire, MacReady ! - Get back ! Just wait !
- 我们太激动了！ - 等一下！
- We're on fire ! - Just wait !
很好，上！
All right, go !
温都思！ 温都思，进来！
Windows ! Windows, get in here !
这真他妈荒谬！
You gotta be fuckin' kidding.
- 你怎么想的，麦克瑞德？ - 一点小测试。
- What do you got in mind, MacReady ? - A little test.
温都思， 你和帕尔马把每个人都捆紧点儿。
Windows, you and Palmer tie everybody down real tight.
- 干嘛？ - 为了你们的健康。
- What for ? - For your health.
我们干掉他吧！ 他不能一下把我们都烧掉！
Let's rush him ! He's not gonna blow us all up !
不，不，等一会儿。 等一会儿。
No, no, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
我们照着麦克说的做！
Let's do what Mac says.
他把诺瑞斯瞬间就干掉了，不是吗 ?
I mean, he wasted Norris pretty quick, didn't he ?
太近了，克拉克。
That's close enough, Clark.
- 他别想把我绑起来。 - 那么我只好杀了你。
- He ain't tyin' me up. - Then I'll have to kill you.
那就来杀我啊。
Then kill me.
我就是这个意思。
I mean it.
我猜你会这么干的。
I guess you do.
- 这真是扯淡，麦克！ - 把它干完，帕尔马。
- This is bullshit, Mac ! - Finish it, Palmer.
他们死了，麦克！
They're dead, Mac !
- 温都思？ - 嗯？
- Windows ? - Yo ?
你过去把帕尔马捆牢。
You tie up Palmer over here.
我们要从每人那里提取一点儿血液。
We're gonna draw a little bit of everybody's blood.
因为我们要找出谁是那个变异体。
'Cause we're gonna find out who's the thing.
看诺瑞斯变异启发了我
Watching Norris in there gave me the idea that...
也许他的每个部分都是一个整体。
maybe every part of him was a whole.
每一小块都是一个单独的生物…
Every little piece was an individual animal...
都有内在保护自己生命的本能。
with a built-in desire to protect its own life.
你们看，当一个人流血，
You see, when a man bleeds,
他流出的只是血液组织。
it's just tissue.
但是当变异体的血液受到袭击， 它是不会服从的。
But blood from one of you things won't obey when it's attacked.
它会试图存活，
It'll try and survive;
所以会从热的针旁爬走。
crawl away from a hot needle, say.
现在该你了。
Now you.
很好。
That's good.
很好，拿过来，到这儿来。
All right, move back. Over there.
我猜你没事。
I guess you're okay.
没事，把那个放上，看着他们。
All right, put that on and watch them.
现在我要让你们看到我已经知道的。
Now I'll show you what I already know.
都是一派胡言。
That's a crock of shit.
让我们试试博士和克拉克。
Let's try the Doc and Clark.
现在该克拉克了。
Now Clark.
那么说克拉克是人类，嗯？
Then Clark was human, huh ?
你这个凶手，不是吗？
Which makes you a murderer, don't it ?
现在该帕尔马了。
Palmer now.
这是胡说。 这证明不了什么。
This is pure nonsense. It doesn't prove a thing.
我想你也这么认为，格瑞。
I thought you'd feel that way, Garry.
你是唯一一个曾经 有可能接触过血液的。
You were the only one that could have got to that blood.
我们最后作你的测试。
We'll do you last.
从我身边离开！ 麦克瑞德，烧它！
Get away from me ! MacReady, burn it !
- 它是什么？
- What is it ?
抓住他！抓住他！射击啊！
Get him, get him ! Just shoot !
- 麦克瑞德，射击啊！
- MacReady, shoot !
- 抓住它，麦克！ 抓住它！
- Get it, Mac ! Get it !
温都思！烧了他！
Windows ! Blast him !
把我从这椅子上放开！
Get me outta here !
温都思！
Windows !
可恶！把我放开！
Damn ! Get me outta here !
- 麦克瑞德！
- MacReady !
- 进来！ - 快，快点儿！赶快！
- Get in here ! - Quick, come on ! Hurry up !
它回来了！烧死它！ 看在上帝份上，烧死它！
It's coming back ! Burn it ! Burn it, for God's sake !
- 烧死它！烧死它！ - 赶快，麦克瑞德！
- Burn it ! Burn it ! - Hurry up, MacReady !
我们开始干吧！
Let's do it.
把我从椅子上放开！给我松绑！
Get me outta here ! Cut me loose !
该死，给我松绑！ 快来，让我从这儿出去！
Cut me the hell- Come on, get me outta here !
快来，把我从椅子上放开！ 给我松绑！该死的！
Come on, get me outta here ! Cut me loose, damn it !
朋友们，我知道你们经历了许多考验，
I know you gentlemen have been through a lot,
但是已经有了结果的时候，
but when you find the time,
我可不想把这个冬天剩下的时间…
I'd rather not spend the rest of this winter...
都耗在这该死的长椅上！
tied to this fucking couch !
乔德斯…
Childs...
我们准备出去给布莱尔作个测试。
we're goin' out to give Blair the test.
如果他把那东西带回来， 并且我们没和他在一起。
If he tries to make it back and we're not with him,
就烧死他。
burn him.
麦克，门是开着的。
Mac, the door is open.
他怎么出去的？ 这个门是从外面锁上的。
How'd he get out ? The door was bolted from the outside.
布莱尔？
Blair ?
嗨，布莱尔！你在下面吗？
Hey, Blair ! You down there ?
我们有些东西给你！
We got something for ya !
布莱尔忙着一个人干这些活呢。
Blair's been busy out here all by himself.
- 什么东西？ - 他做的东西。
- What is it ? - Something he's been making.
好象是某种船。
It's a ship of some kind.
他从直升飞机上偷的零件。
He stole the parts from the helicopter.
这个狗娘养的真聪明。 把这些零件一件一件组装到一起。
Smart s.o.b. He put it together piece by piece.
他准备往哪儿跑？
Where was he tryin' to go ?
除了这儿的任何地方。
Anyplace but here.
嗨，伙计们，来这儿。快来。
Hey, you guys, come here. Come here.
我想我看见乔德斯 在营地的主入口外面。
I think I saw Childs outside the main entrance of the camp.
- 他在外面干什么？ - 我不知道。
- What's he doing outside ? - I don't know.
你有烟火吗？
Got a flare ?
他要回去关掉发电机。
He got back inside and blew the generator.
在6个小时内， 这里就会降到零下100度
In six hours, it'll be 100 below in here.
啊，那是自杀！
Well, that's suicide !
不是为那个。
Not for that thing.
它想把自己冻起来。
It wants to freeze now.
它没办法从这儿出去。 它只好先休眠，直到救援队找到他。
It's got no way outta here. It just wants to go to sleep until the rescue team finds it.
那么我们怎么办？ 那么我们怎么办？
What can we do ? What can we do ?
不管我们是否能行， 我们不能让这个变异体再次冷冻。
Whether we make it or not, we can't let that thing freeze again.
也许我们该让这周围暖和起来。
Maybe we'll just warm things up a little around here.
我们没法活着从这儿出去…
We're not gettin' outta here alive...
那东西也不能。
but neither is that thing.
发电机室。
Generator room.
发电机完了。
Generator's gone.
还能修理吗？
Anyway we can fix it ?
是说它没了，麦克瑞德。
It's gone, MacReady.
很好。我们要让这地方整个埋到冰下。
All right. We gotta bring this whole place right down into the ice.
格瑞，在旧贮藏室安置你的东西。
Garry, plant yours in the old storage room.
诺斯，下去到发电机那里。
Nauls, down by the generator.
哦，我的上帝。
Oh, God.
它怎么进来的？
How's it comin' in there ?
- 我是说，“它怎么…”
- I said, "How's it-"
是，你他妈的。
Yeah, fuck you too !
你一个干的？
You the only one who made it ?
不只我一个。
Not the only one.
你把它杀了？
Did you kill it ?
你在哪儿，乔德斯？
Where were you, Childs ?
我在想我看见了布莱尔。
Thought I saw Blair.
我在他后面出去的…
I went out after him...
然后在暴风雪里迷路了。
and got lost in the storm.
火让整个营地的温度都升高了。
Fires got the temperature up all over the camp.
这不会持续太长时间的。
Won't last long though.
我们也不会。
Neither will we.
我们怎么做？
How will we make it ?
也许我们不应该。
Maybe we shouldn't.
如果你是在担心我，
If you're worried about me-
如果我们互相猜疑，
If we've got any surprises for each other,
我认为我们什么也干不成
I don't think we're in much shape to do anything about it.
好吧…我们该做什么？
Well... what do we do ?
我们为什么不…
Why don't we just...
在这儿等一会儿，
wait here for a little while,
看看还会发生什么。
see what happens.
好的。
Yeah.